you got there before the
вы попали ээ ещё до того как была
Russian Empire existed you got into the Soviet
Российская империя вы попали в Советский
Union so yeah honestly I get it and how did you
Союз так да чест понял а как вы после
get into the Russian Empire after the Soviet Union
Советского Союза попали в Российскую
I'm telling you like we didn't get
я тебе говорю типа то что мы не попадали
into the Russian Empire we only got into the
не в Российскую империю мы попали только
Soviet Union that is they just found us
в Советский Союз то есть нас нашли
and that's it I mean they found you they found us they
просто и всё в смысле вас нашли нас
found us in the
нашли нас нашли в
forest by chance my
лесу случайно
grandfather
мне дед
told me about let's have a normal chat
рассказал о давай нормально пообщаемся
hello I'm from the city of Khmelnitsky
да здравствуйте я из города Хмельницкой
Ukraine you're from Russia where is
Украины ты из России откуда
Magadan I get it and what are you by nationality Even
магадан понял а ты по национальности кто
Even I get it well Even or Eveng Even Even
эвен эвен понял ну Эвен или Эвенг эвен
these are different peoples Even Evens
эвен это же разные народы ивен ивенки
so yeah I get it because many from Russia do
так да понял потому что многие из России
n't even know I also met
даже не знают я тоже встречал как-то
people somehow I mean they don't know everyone knows well
людей в смысле не знают все знают ну
many from Russia don't understand that there are
многие из России не понимают что есть
Evens there are Evens that they
ивены есть ивенки что они по-разному все
understand everything differently everyone understands everything in Moscow or in St. Petersburg
понимают в Москве либо в Петербурге
only like that but in the rest of
только так понимают а ну в остальной
Russia they understand everything I get it you're
России всё понимает понял ты сейчас как
like serving now or are you sitting at home just
типа служишь или это дома сидишь просто
serving on vacation now a contract soldier
служу отпуске сейчас контрактник
yes I
да
get it and what did you go on a contract
понял а что пошёл на контракт
and  that I went and just wanted to go and
а что пошёл да захотелось просто пойти и
still think because of the money or something I'm not just
всё думаете из-за денег что ли не просто
asking yes no of course I have nothing to do
спрашиваю да нет конечно я делать нечего
there watched enough of those war videos
там насмотрелся на этих военных роликах
there to run and shoot there to jump there of
там побегать пострелять там попрыгать
course well that's all and but it
там конечно ну как бы и всё а а там
turns out there is still
оказывается деньги ещё есть ни там там
money there it turns out they still pay
оказывается ещё деньги платят ну
well cool yes I stayed
прикольно да я остался
listen but how do you feel about the fact
слушай а вот как ты относишься к тому
that Moscow takes from all regions
что Москва забирает со всех регионов в
including Chukotka yes from
том же числе и с Чукотки да вот с
Magadan uh all the
Магдана ээ все
resources so and sends people to fight
ресурсы так а отправляет людей воевать
Muscovites themselves St. Petersburgers do not fight but
сами москвичи питерцы не воюют а вот
people like from different nations Avens
людей таких как с разных народов Авенов
Khakass Sakha Buryats are sent to die
Хакасов Саха отправляют бурятов умирают
for Russia why is it suddenly so it
за Россию с чего это вдруг так
seems to you no well that's how it is
это вам так кажется не ну так и есть
because I looked at the statistics of the dead
потому что я смотрел статистику погибших
the largest one hundred percent of the dead in
самая большая ста процентээ погибших по
relation to the number of residents of the
соотношению к количеству жителей
region are from all these republics and
региона- это с вот этих всех республик и
distant regions Moscow and St. Petersburg have the
дальних регионов у Москвы и Питера самый
smallest
меньший
seriously yes well let's
серьёзно да
say I am from Magadan for some reason I did
ну вот я допустим с Магадана почему-то я
not die well someone  he said: "You
не умер же ну кто-то говорил: "У тебя же
definitely have a bunch of dead acquaintances"
по-любому есть куча погибших знакомых"
is it true
правда
yes no I have them all alive yes not all this is
да нет у меня все живые да не всё это
just nonsense there is not a single one under Look look
просто бред нет ни одного под Смотри
everything look look and we also don't have no
смотри всё смотри смотри и у нас также
look in this war there is not a
нет ни смотри на этой войне нет ни
single unit in which everyone is alive well with
одного подразделения у кого все живые
us everyone is alive yes I don't agree everything you
ну у нас все живые да не согласи всё ты
just no look you are lying
просто нет смотри ты обманываешь потому
because in Russia there is not a single unit
что нет в России ни одного подразделения
in which everyone is alive no and you like
в котором все живые нету а у вас как
wait losses see you are running away now
подожди потери видишь ты сейчас убегаешь
like you like you because you are
как у вас как у вас потому что ты
afraid to answer no no well like you are you
боишься ответить не нет ну как у вас ты
afraid I don't know I'm not a military man I'm not a
боишься я не знаю я же не военный я не
military man I'm not me Look you immediately
военный я не Я Смотрите вы сразу
start saying that I don't get involved in these
начинаете говорить что я не влажу в эти
matters and you are a military man yes but I know that in
дела а ты военный да но я знаю что в
Russia there is not a single unit
России ни в одном подразделении потому
because I watched Russian bloggers yes they
что я смотрел российских блогеров да они
say there is not a single unit in which there
говорят ни в одном подразделении нет
were no losses in any of
такой чтобы не было потерь ни в одном
my units for some reason and you are probably
у меня все живые почему-то а вы наверное
rear troops yes you are somewhere why well you
тыловые войска да вы где-то почему ну вы
weren't name which unit I am
не были назови какое подразделение я
now  I'll check the losses anyway, there are,
сейчас проверю потери по-любому есть
dial Botur, what kind of Botur, you
наберите ботур что за ботур
see, you don't even know what Well, what,
вот видите вы даже не знаете что Ну что
explain what Botur is, Botur is an
так объясните что такое Ботур ботур -
assault squad, an
это штурмовой отряд
assault squad, Bor, come on, Botu, yes, yes, yes, yes, now,
штурмовой отряд Бор
now, let's see, everyone is still
так сейчас сейчас сейчас посмотрим все
alive, no, no, don't wait, you
живые остались нене не подожди
start right away, oh, you see, you have there,
вот сразу начинаете о видите у вас там у
you have there, give me a look, also on November
вас там дайте во смотри ещё ноябрь
22, uh, a Russian fighter of the
двадцать второго ээ российский погибший
SVO, fighters of the Yakut detachment Botur, who died in the zone,
в зоне боец СВО бойцов якутского отряда
received a serious injury, died in the
получил тяжёлый наране скончался в
hospital,
госпитале
seven, look, Seven, this is only news
семи смотри Семерых это только новость
for November 22, for example,
за ноябрь двадцать второго например
seven Yakuts, yes, the detachment lost seven Yakuts
семерых Якутян да семерых якутян отряд
in the heaviest bloody battle on
потерял в самой тяжёлой кровой битве 24
September 24, that's already you, that is, you're already
сентября вот тебе уже то есть ты уже
deceiving that there were no losses, no, but on the
обманываешь что не было никаких потерь
twenty-
нет ну а двадцать
fifth, well, there was one person each, there was one
пятого ну там же по одному же человеку
person each, no, well, look, you've already
человеку было не ну смотри ты уже
deceived, look, you've already deceived, agree to the deception,
обманул смотри ты уже обману согласись
look, you told me, I told you  found it right away
смотри ты сказал я тебе сходу нашёл
found the dead yes
сходу нашёл погибших да
one person no not one also one
одного человека нет не одного тож один
right away and seven already at least eight in
сразу и семь уже как минимум восемь в
one news seriously yes I
одной новости серьёзно да я же тебе
read it to you seriously
зачитал серьёзно
so on and on stop missing missing
так дальше дальше стоп пропавшие
in action are in Baatur there are
пропавшие с безвести есть в Баатуре есть
I read because yes Sahade writes yes
я читаю потому что вот да Сахаде пишет
relatives yes six here twenty-second
да родные да шесть вот двадцать второй
year six dead are still
год шестеро погибших по-прежнему
considered missing in action to
считаются безвести пропавшими чтобы
recognize their death it is necessary to find the bodies
признать их смерть нужно разыскать тела
there relatives held a rally yes yes yes
там родственники митинг делали дадада
what year is this this is still twenty-second I
это каком году это ещё двадца второй я
look and
смотрю а
this is A twenty-fifth d trade fours now
это А двадца пятый д трейд четы сейчас
wait
подожди
and how many people did you have in your squad
а отряд сколько человек у вас был
13 people no well look this is boutur
13 человек не ну смотри вот это боутур
squad how many it says here 60 people
отряд сколько тут пишет 60 человек
13 people and look if eight
13 человек во и смотри если восемь
dead this is out of how many there were
погибших это из скольки было
I am telling you that 13 people are in boutur I
я тебе говорю то что 13 человек в ботре
understood everything and eight of them
находится понял всё и восемь из них
died it was yes
погибло было да
this was in twenty-second yes yes yes well
это в двадцать втором году да да да ну
look in general for all the time in a year no here
смотри вообще за всё время в год нет вот
you here you tell me in twenty-fifth
ты вот ты мне скажи в двадцать пятом
again again  look at you yes during the
году ещё раз ещё раз смотри у вас да за
whole time of Botur how many people were there and
всё время Ботура сколько было людей и
how many died during the whole time yes well
сколько погибших за всё время да
probably
ну человек наверное
six to seven people I don't know how you say like
шесть-7м не знаю как ты говоришь типа
eight and look again you you
восемь а ещё раз смотри ещё раз ты ты
take some
берёшь каких-то
scum how many 60 people he writes over there
шеряд сколько 60 человек вон там пишет
yes
да
no I'm asking you but let's say
нет я я тебя спрашиваю а а вот допустим
in Ukraine let's say Okay I got it tell me look tell me
на Украине допустим Ладно понял скажи
why did you go everything let's
смотри скажи зачем ты пошёл всё давай
look let's forget everything I got it you are an
смотри забу забудем всё я понял вы
immortal squad tell me why did you
бессмертный отряд ты скажи мне зачем ты
go to kill people in a foreign country you are from
пошёл убивать людей в чужую страну ты из
distant Yakutia yes Sakha went to kill
дальней Якутии да Саха пошёл убивать
people in a foreign country
людей в чужую страну
why
зачем
because the country Russia Russia is a
со потому что страна Россия Россия
country it is my country well Russia is a
страна это это моя страна ну Россия -
country that captured your country yes
это страна которая захватила твою страну
seriously or what well yes well but didn't the
да серьёзно что ли ну да ну а разве
Russians didn't the Russians capture
русские не разве русские не захватили
your territory no like we live
вашу территорию нет как не мы живём
normally now but how did you end up in
нормально сейчас а а как вы попали в
Russia
Россию
and how did you end up well tell me tell me how did you
а вы как попали ну скажи скажи как ты
end up if the Russians didn't capture you
попал если вас не захватили русские
then you somehow came to them yourself or
значит вы как-то сами пришли к ним или
how no but  like they captured
как нет а как то есть захватили они к
us when they came to us gave us
нам при Они к нам пришли дали нам
the opportunity to [ __ ] live normally everything and
возможность нахуй жить нормально всё и
how we live so well
как мы и живём
in what year did they come and let
так ну в каком году они пришли и дали
you live normally well
вам нормально жить
in my understanding it turns out like that in
у в моём понимании получается типа то
wars came to me
пришли ко мне войны
so wait the Russian empire captured
так подожди российская империя захватила
your people a long time ago
твой народ ещё давно
and you are talking about the Yakuts or something well
а ты про якутов что ли
you Even your territories yes your
ну ты Эвен твои территории да твои
territories fell into the Russian empire
территории попали в Российскую империю
before the 20th century no yes no yes now I'll
ещё до XX века нет да нет да сейчас
say dial the village of Berezovka
скажу набери село Берёзовка пятьдесят
1954 in what country is it good
четвёртый год в какой стране она хорошо
in what country was it before
в какой стране она была до пятьдесят
1954 in Siberia and it was in Siberia
четвёртого года в Сибири а в Сибири
all this and that was wait am I
находилась это всё а это было подожди я
right let's dial dial dial
правильно давай набираю набираю набери
please in this 1954 the
набери пожалуйста в этом пятьдесят
village of
село
Berezovka is called 1954 so so what happened
Берёзовка 1954 год тактак что случилось
to this birch tree
с этой берёзокой
well read read
ну почитай прочитай
so uh so ho yes it Ho yes yes
так ээ так хо да оно Хо да да
so a village in Srednekolymskoye  lusRepublic of
так село в Среднеколымском луспублики
Sakha well
Саха ну
well then what then well in
ну дальше и что так дальше ну в
1954 Berezovka became an
1954 году Берёзовка стала
administrative center it was made a
административным центром её сделали
district the center of a district and yes only in
районом центром района и да только в
wait it was in 1954
подожди это в пятьдесят четвёртом году
it was made the center of a small region
её сделали центром региончика
yes yes but it was part of the Russian
да да но она входила в состав Российской
Empire since the 15th century no no
империи ещё с XV века
so let's do it in the 20th
нет нет так давай в XX
century 1954 before Berezovka was
веке 1954 году до того как Берёзовку
made a district center of which
твою сделали районным центром в какое
state was it part of the Russian
государство оно входило в Российскую
Empire and the Soviet Union that's
империю а в Советский Союз
right how did your village end up in the
правильно как твоё село попало в
Soviet Union
Советский Союз
and what do you think no and you
а ты что думаешь не а ты что прочитать
can't read it here it doesn't write how it doesn't write
не можешь тут не пишет как это не пишет
because I'll tell you the Soviet Union
потому что я тебе скажу Советский Союз
it ended up because it was in the
оно попало потому что оно было в
Russian Empire and then remained in the
Российской империи и потом осталось в
Soviet Union what are you saying tell me
Советском Союзе ты что ты а расскажи мне
well look you know the history of your
ну смотри ты лучше знаешь историю своего
village better explain it to me honestly this is how they
села мне честно объясни это это у тебя
write it on Google look yes
так в Гугле пишут смотри да
when in 1954 we
когда вот мы короче в пятьдесят
wandered in short from the war it
году скитались короче от войны
turns out yes
получается да
we wandered from  wars in the sense that you Evens
мы скитались от войны в смысле вы эвены
wandered from the war yes yes so but there
скитались от войны да да так а войны не
was no war at all there was a war here in the European
было вообще война была тут в европейской
part you have there there was no trace of a war from
части у вас там помине войны не было от
what war did you wander
какой войны вы скитались
we were in the Chikotka area
мы находились в районе Чикотки
so okay there was a war
так о'кей там была война
no there were
нет там были
uh how can I tell you
ээ как тебе
look when my great-grandmother in short
смотри когда вот моя прабабушка короче
she saw planes like these yes they were
она видела самолёты вот эти вот да
flying from the
летели со
side of America it turns out she looked like she was saying like what kind of
стороны Америки получается она смотрела
children and
такая типа говорила типа что за дети а
what wait and what and planes from the side of
что подожди а что а самолёты со стороны
America where were they flying
Америки куда летели
from the side from the side of America yes towards the
со стороны со стороны Америки да в
Soviet Union and why were they
сторону Советского Союза а зачем они
flying there what are you
туда летели
zeros
ты что нули
or everything I understand now I understand yes and
али всё понял понял теперь понял да и
look
смотри
it was somewhere 4% shorter than Lanlis and it
это было где-то 4% короче Ланлиза и
turns out
получается смотри
look it was only from this from the side of America and it turns out look and
Америки и получается смотри и
watched what's his name there like
смотрел как его там как
his film or I don't know there like
его фильм или не знаю там как бы
there was a play two banks one victory
там спектакль два берега одно победа
watched no no I didn't watch I
смотрел нет не не смотрел
advise you to watch yeah what are two
советую посмотреть угу что такое два
banks of one victory so so what your
берега одной победы тактак то что твоя
grandmother saw planes and
бабушка видела самолёты и
I told you what like damn she  she
я тебе то что сказал типа что блин она
said something like what the hell are these big birds
сказала типа что за блин птицы такие
flying around and we were in the forest then the
летают а мы находились в лесу тогда
war ended
так война закончилась
then I tell you
потом я тебе рассказываю
then in short when after the
потом короче когда вот после
post-war
послевоенные
years you say something like that in
годы вы говорите типа то что вот вот на
Kolyma everything was bad there Kolyma there
Колыме там всё было плохо Колыма там
like there Gulak archipelago Gulak with
типа там гулак архипелаг гулак тим
Solzhenitsyn back and forth like yeah well like that
солженицем туда-сюда вот типа да ну как
it's all a lie
бы там это всё враньё на самом
in fact it wasn't like that in fact that
деле не было такого на самом деле то
is Slazhenitsyn writes something like that
есть Слаженицн пишет типа то что типа
he ate 3 tons
вот он там 3 тона вкушал
like mammoths there he ate like
типа мамонтов там он кушал там типа мясо
mammoth meat there he gobbled it up there back and forth in
мамонта он хавал там типа туда-сюда
short it's
короче это это враньё
all a lie that is mammoth meat
всё то есть мясо мамонтова ты
imagine what the hell mammoth meat
представь который блин мясо мамонтово
it's been lying there for 20,000 years 500,000 years it's been
она там лежит там 20.000 лет 500.000 лет
lying there naturally what will it do
там лежит она естественно что сделает
of course there will be nothing left of that meat and
конечно ей там от этого мяса ничего не
these newts well you do the math yourself
а тритоны вот эти вот ну ты посчитай сам
Solzhenitsyn yeah this is this this is
солженицана угу это это это это это
some kind of nonsense archipelago  gulak there something there
какой-то архипелаг гулак там что-то там
like there it's just
типа там это это вообще
nonsense read and you read I just didn't
бред почитайте а ты читал я просто не
read dump woman you read
читал свал женицна ты читал
yes
да
he says something like that I ate these
он говорит типа то что я кушал этих
3tons that in the spring they
3тонов которые весной они
thaw and we started
оттаивают и мы начинали их
eating them how so 3tons they are like toads it
кушать это как так 3тоны они как жабы же
turns out yes aphibi in theory
получается же да афиби по идее
yes and slozhnits wrote something like that
да а сложениц написал типа то что якобы
we allegedly ate them there like that's nonsense and
мы их кушали там типа это же бред же и
he ate mammoth meat
он кушал мясо мамонта
I live in Yakutia I've never seen
я вот живу в Якутии ни разу не видел
mammoth meat at all never never yes we
мяса мамонта вообще ни разу
find mammoth tusks well
никогда да находим бивне мамонта ну мясо
mammoth meat has never been
мамонта никогда не
found you puzzled me I'll read read read understand understand
находили ты меня озадачил я почитаю
then
почитайте почитайте понял понял то
tell me how did you Evenno got into the
расскажи как вы Эвенно попали в
Russian Empire
Российскую империю
we didn't get into the
в Российскую империю мы попали не в
Russian Empire we got into
Российскую империю мы попали
but where did we get back in Soviet times we
а куда мы попали ещё в советское время
got and even before the Russian
ещё попали мы а ещё до Российской
Empire back in Soviet times we got in it
империи ещё в советское время попали да
turns out in the fifty-fourth year
получается в пятьдесят четвёртом году
here I am  I told you in
вот я же я же вам говорил же в пятьдесят
1954, you google it, I
четвёртом году вот вы прогуглиете я
googled it, and in 1954, the
прогуглил да пять четёт четвёртом году
village of Berezok, like, here we are, like,
село Берёзок вот вот типа вот мы вот
then we were found, all this time, I
тогда вот мы нашлись всё это время в
mean, we were found, and you were lost, yes,
смысле нашлись а вы потерянные были да
we are a nomadic people, well,
мы мы кочевой народ
yes, a nomadic people, on our own territories,
ну да кочевой народ на своих территориях
and what, yes, on our own territories, and that
и что да на своих территориях и что вот
they came and, as if, they didnt do anything bad to us, do
они пришли и как бы нам ничего плохого
you think that we
сделали вы думаете то что мы сейчас
live poorly now, no, I see, you
плохо живём нет не я вижу вы хорошо
live well, educated, smart people, like, in
живёте образованные умные люди типа в
abundance, yes, and
достатке да
then no, its just interesting, but look, it
дальше нене просто интересно а смотри
turns out that you ended up, uh, even before the
получается что вы попали ээ ещё до того
Russian Empire existed, you ended up in the Soviet
как была Российская империя вы попали в
Union, yes, I understand, and how did you
Советский Союз так да понял а как вы
end up in the Russian Empire after the Soviet Union,
после Советского Союза попали в
Im telling you, like, we didnt end up
я тебе говорю типа то что мы не попадали
in the Russian Empire, we only ended up
не в Российскую империю мы попали только
in the Soviet Union, and Im telling you,
в Советский Союз и тебе я тебе же
in
в пятьдесят четвёртом
1954, that is, they simply found us and thats it, I
году то есть нас нашли просто и всё в
mean, they found you, they found us, they found us in the
смысле вас нашли нашли нас нашли в
forest
лесу
by chance, my grandfather told me so, and  well
случайно мне дед рассказал так а ну
tell me this story that is, it
расскажи вот эта история то есть
turns out that you were accidentally found in the forest and
получается вас случайно нашли в лесу и
what did they do to you, what did they do, they did nothing,
что с вами сделали что
they said something
сделали ничего не сделали они сказали
like, now you are under Soviet
типа что вот теперь вы под советской
rule, like everything is fine, they gave us an
властью типа всё хорошо дали нам
education, as you can see,
образование как видите
everything is fine, I live and
вот всё хорошо вот я живу и нормально
everything is fine, so wait, but what if your grandfather, my
всё так подожди а если бы вас дед мой
grandfather, he is against, uh, Soviet
дед дед мой он против ээ советского
education, he doesnt want to
образования ничего ничего не хочет
say anything, he has two years of education
сказать у него два класса образования
now, by the way, he is still alive now, by the way,
сейчас он сейчас до сих пор кстати жив
and he speaks well of the Soviet
и он хорошо отзывается насчёт советской
power, he says something like, if there were
власти он говорит типа была бы сейчас
Soviet
советская
power now, it would be Listen, do I
власть было бы Слушай я правильно
understand correctly that it turns out that if in
понимаю что получается если бы в
1954 you had not been accidentally found in the forest, you would
1954 вас случайно не нашли в лесу вы до
still be living there in the forest, yes,
сих пор бы там в лесу жили да
and do you remember at least that you have a portrait of the
а вы помните хоть у вас есть портрет
person who found you in the forest,
человека который вас нашёл в лесу
yes, who found you, an
да кто вас нашёл
ordinary Cossack, what kind of Cossack was in the Soviet
казак обычный какой казак в Советском
Union,
Союзе
I dont know, I just dont know what kind of Cossacks were
я не знаю просто я не знаю какие казаки
in 1954, you dont know what, damn,
в пятьдесят четвёртом году ты не знаешь
in the Soviet Union, a Cossack, a Cossack, Do
то что блин в Советском Союзе каза каза
you think there
Ты что думаешь казаков не было что ли
were no Cossacks, or were there Cossacks, so what kind of Cossacks were they, where did
были казаки так а что за казаки откуда
they come from,
они пришли
calculate these, these people,
просчитай вот этих вот этих вот людей
exactly,
вот именно
right now in  Google write the upper crosses
ээ сейчас в Гугле напиши верхние кресты
on Kolyma the upper crosses of
на Колыме верхние кресты
Dani they find the upper crosses only
дани находят верхние кресты только
Orthodox crosses on
православные кресты на
Kolyma Krestovka tributary of Kolyma there are
Колыме крестовка приток Колымы есть
no upper crosses
нету верхние кресты
nothing tell me the
ничего расскажи мне
upper crosses what is this this
верхние кресты то что это
was before Stalin's times like
это ещё было до сталинских времён типа
there this before 917 so they found us it
там вот это до 917 года вот они нас
turns out they found us in this on the Kolomeya River
получается ещё в этом на реке Коломея
itself so wait you were found you were found
самой так подожди вас нашли вас нашли
before 1917 or in 1954 this is
ещё до 1917 года или в 1954 это это
Yakuts found this Yakuts were found and Yakuts
Якутов нашли это Якутов нашли а Якутов
were found in 1917 and you were found in 1954
нашли в 1917 а вас нашли в 1954
no in short the
нет короче
Yakuts were founded in
якутов основали в 1943
1943 type 194 so so so this is Sakha
году набери 194 так так так это Саха
Yakutia but the Yakuts lived there yes it was a long time
Якутию но якуты же там жили ещё да было
ago and you think like who are the Yakuts who
давно-давно а ты думаешь типа якуты -
are the Yakuts the Yakuts are those
это кто кто это якуты якуты - это те
people who are like former Mongols
люди которые это типа бывшие монголы
like there no it's like the Kazakhs are Turks yes like the
типа там нет это как казахи тюрки да вот
Kazakhs are Altaians there they
как казахи алтайцы там они получается
came  to our lands to us yeah yeah
пришли на наши земли к нам угу
yeah wait what are your lands if your
и так подожди какие ваши земли если ваши
lands you were only found in 1954 in the
земли вас только нашли в 1954 году в
forest
лесу
I'm explaining to you verbatim
я тебе я тебе и объясняю вот дословно
first at first the Far East was populated by these that
сначала Дальний Восток заселяли вот вот
like there Primorye there
эти вот то что вот типа там Приморье там
Volsto tribes
Волсто племена
that is earlier you
то есть раньше вы
Yes it was us there Chupchi
Да это это были мы там Чупчи
Evens and so on Ulchi Yakaghirs yes yeah here are the
эвены и так дальше ульчи якагиры да да
Kamchadals all of these that is these are
вот Камчадалы вот эти вот все вот то
our lands that is we are
есть это это наши земли были то есть мы
primitive people there that is Tatalova
первобытные люди там то есть Таталова
in short were there yeah
короче были там угу
then came in short Buryats
потом пришли короче туда буряты
Kazakhs Mongols that is there like well you
казахи монголы то есть там как бы ну
understand yes how would you like
понимаешь да как бы тебе вот как бы
then came white people as we
потом пришли вот белые люди как мы
say yes white people that is these are
говорим да белые люди то есть это
Russian white people - these are Russians like
русские белые люди - это русские как бы
and you are not white
а ты не белый
compared to Russians I am generally
по сравнению с русскими я вообще как
like a black person understood so
бы чернокожий человек понял
and then these white Russians came
так так и потом пришли эти белые русские
and that Russian whites came they gave us
и что русские белые пришли они нам дали
like food guns these like there these like
как бы пропитание ружия вот эти вот типа
there  well, like they
там вот эти вот ну как бы там ну как бы
gave him metal there, well, like the
металл короче дали там ну как бы там
Mongols didn't have metal, not
у монголов металла не было не
just wondering how to explain it to you,
просто интересуюсь как тебе объяснить-то
damn, don't hang out,
блин
please, hang up, this is a
пожалуйста это
character, oh, damn, we'll never know what the
персонаж ай блин мы так и не узнаем что
White Russians brought,
белые русские принесли
well, hang up,
ну ну развине
[music]
[музыка]
hang up, damn, we're waiting, we're waiting, we're
развисни
waiting, now the intrigue is maybe it will hang up, it's
блин ждём ждём ждём сейчас интрига может
unlikely, but
маловероятно но
maybe the Russians came, gave him a gun, and
может русские пришли дали ружие и
sent him to die in Ukraine, that wasn't it, it was awesome,
послали его умирать в Украину
this is a clear
не это было бомбезно вот это яркий
example of how Russia
пример того как Россия из разных
makes such people out of different indigenous peoples, just without
коренных народов делает таких просто без
mankurts, like, subscribe,
манкуртов лайк подписка
comment, subscribe to my Instagram, I don't
комент підпишись на мій Instagram я не
know why you need this, why else should I
знаю для чго це тобі для чго ще тобі там
look at the rest, but it's one, two,
дивитись на ост але для тебе це один два
or three clicks for you, but you support me and I
або три клика але ти підтримаєш мене и я
'll say: "Wow, I have a bunch of
буду казати: "Вау в мене там купа
followers and  I'll be cool,
фоловерів и в мене буде класний
write to me on my Instagram, priest
настропись на мій Instagram попик
Andrey"
Андрей"
otakchik, let me screw you up
отакчик давай я тебя очекаю